Guide to the Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects records RL.11425
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects records
1996-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects (SWOOP)
RL.11425
3.0 Linear Feet
Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects (SWOOP) was a non-profit organization in Raleigh, NC that performed community service projects to help people and organizations in need of home repair and landscaping. The collection includes a series of photo albums and binders documenting SWOOP projects, as well as administrative materials. The binders include correspondence with partner organizations and SWOOP members as well as newsletters and notices about upcoming projects. Board meeting minutes, organizational efforts in the wake of Hurricane Fran, and publicity materials are also included in the collection.
Biographical / Historical
Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects (SWOOP) was a community-based non-profit organization founded in 1996 after a group of 16 women in Raleigh came together to perform practical community service projects in the wake of Hurricane Fran. The group performed home repair and landscaping projects. Afterward, they continued their work and expanded their membership. The organization's stated mission is one of cooperative sisterhood to meet the needs of the community.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Strong Women Organizing Outrageous Projects (SWOOP) records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of a group of albums and binders that document SWOOP's projects, and a series of materials that document the group's organizational history. The albums contain photographs that document project work days, as well as descriptions of the projects and their locations. The binders contain correspondence with partner organizations and other relevant parties, information about ongoing projects, as well as newsletters and notices about upcoming events and projects. The administrative files comprise mostly board meeting materials, as well as newspaper clippings and publicity.
Do-it-yourself work -- North Carolina -- Raleigh; Women -- North Carolina -- Raleigh -- Societies and clubs; Women construction workers -- North Carolina -- Raleigh; Women gardeners -- North Carolina -- Raleigh; Women volunteers in social service -- North Carolina -- Raleigh; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Project Documentation, 1999-2006
  - Photograph Albums, 2005-2006 and undated; 2 albums (Box 1)
  - Project Binders, 1996-2002; 3 Volumes (Box 1)
- Administrative Materials, 1996-2016
  - Board Meetings, 2004-2015; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Project and Event Documentation, 2004-2016 (Box 2)
  - Governor's Proclamation, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Newsletters (Box 2)
  - Bylaws and Incorporation (Box 2)
  - Strong Women and Heroes Projects, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Whoopin' it up for SWOOP Programs (Box 2)
  - Hurricane Fran, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Publicity, 1997-2014 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1997-2000s (Box 2)
  - Thank Yous, 2003-2015 (Box 2)
  - Awards, 2001-2012 (Box 2)